Guide to the Fire Department of the City of New York Logbooks and Reports 1870-1957 MS 0210
New-York Historical Society
Fire Department of the City of New York Logbooks and Reports
1870-1957
New-York Historical Society
New York (N.Y.). Fire Department
MS 0210
4.5 Linear feet 51 volumes
Collection of logbooks and reports from the Fire Department of the City of New York. Logbooks from various Engine Companies and Hook and Ladder Companies constitute the majority of the collection. These volumes date from 1870 to 1957, and document the day-to-day workings of the firehouses. Additional volumes, dated 1893-1913, contain Fire Chiefs' records, assignments to duty, and fire alarm signals.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series:
Series I: Engine Company logbooks (arranged by company number)
Series II: Hook and Ladder Company logbooks (arranged by company number)
Series III: Reports (arranged by type of report)
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase, 2013 (volume 35).
Gift of James Drew, 2023 (volumes 29 and 31).
Donor information is lacking for other volumes.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of logbooks and reports from the Fire Department of the City of New York, dating from 1870 to 1957. Logbooks chronicle the daily activities of various FDNY Engine companies and Hook and Ladder companies. Entries record roll call, meals, firemen going on/off street patrol or house patrol, alarms received, care of horses, equipment checks, etc. Most volumes list the names and addresses of the company's firemen. Entries in red ink are by officers; entries in black ink by other members of the company. Also included are volumes containing chiefs' records, alarm signals, and duty assignments.
Related Materials
Five additional logbooks were cataloged individually, before this collection was processed:
BV New York City -Fire Fire Engine Company No. 10
BV New York City - Fire Fire Engine Company No. 11
BV New York City - Fire Hook and Ladder Company No. 3
BV New York City - Fire Hook and Ladder Company No. 15
BV Brooklyn Fire Engine No. 6
Fire fighters -- New York (State) -- New York.; Fire stations.
- Series I: Engine Company Logbooks, 1870-1957
  - Engine Company 2, July-December 1918 (Volume 1)
  - Engine Company 5, July-November 1880 (Volume 2)
  - Engine Company 6, August 1871-March 1872 (Volume 3)
  - Engine Company 6, July-Decemeber 1884 (Volume 4)
  - Engine Company 7, July-December 1898 (Volume 5)
  - Engine Company 7, April 1956-February 1957 (Volume 6)
  - Engine Company 7, March-September 1957 (Volume 7)
  - Engine Company 9, July-December 1872 (Volume 8)
  - Engine Company 9, August 1873-June 1874 (Volume 9)
  - Engine Company 10, May-December 1875 (Volume 10)
  - Engine Company 13, June-October 1896 (Volume 11)
  - Engine Company 14, December 1951-August 1952 (Volume 12)
  - Engine Company 18, July 1875-March 1876 (Volume 13)
  - Engine Company 21, May-September 1879 (Volume 14)
  - Engine Company 22, February-May 1904 (Volume 15)
  - Engine Company 24, December 1873-June 1874 (Volume 16)
  - Engine Company [26], May-November 1870 (Volume 17)
  - Engine Company 28, June 1871-June 1872 (Volume 18)
  - Engine Company 36, June-September 1929 (Volume 19)
  - Engine Company 45, December 1897-April 1898 (Volume 20)
  - Engine Company 50, July-October 1911 (Volume 21)
  - Engine Company 82, July-October 1907 (Volume 41)
    Scope and Contents
    Engine 82 and Hook and Ladder 31 share one volume.
  - Engine Company 157, May-September 1922 (Volume 22)
  - Engine Company 159, October 1913-February 1914 (Volume 23)
  - Engine Company 202, March-August 1895 (Volume 24)
  - Engine Company 203, December 1900-May 1901 (Volume 25)
  - Engine Company 204, August-December 1917 (Volume 26)
  - Engine Company 205, August-November 1922 (Volume 27)
  - Engine Company 209, July-November 1922 (Volume 28)
  - Engine Company 274, March-September 1927 (Volume 29)
  - Engine Company 297, August 1925-January 1926 (Volume 30)
  - Engine Company -- [unidentified] [sealed] (Volume 31)
- Series II: Hook and Ladder Company Logbooks, 1885-1907
  - Hook and Ladder Company 1, November 1889-March 1890 (Volume 32)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 1, October 1900-January 1901 (Volume 33)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 9, October 1885-January 1886 (Volume 34)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 10, September 1874-February 1875 (Volume 35)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 11, April-July 1903 (Volume 36)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 12, November 1927- March 1928 (Volume 37)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 14, June-October 1899 (Volume 38)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 19, December 1885-March 1886 (Volume 39)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 24, November 1912-January 1913 (Volume 40)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 31, July-October 1907 (Volume 41)
- Series III: Reports, 1893-1913
  - Assignments to Duty, Bronx, 1903 (Volume 42)
  - Assignments to Duty, Manhattan, 1907 (Volume 43)
  - Assignments to Duty, Bronx, 1909 (Volume 44)
  - Chief's Record, 12th Battalion, April 1893-January 1895 (Volume 45)
  - Chief's Record, 27th Battalion, August 1902-December 1903 (Volume 46)
  - Chief's Record, Engine Company 101, February 1910- January 1913 (Volume 47)
  - Fire Alarm Signals Class 15, Manhattan and Bronx, 1907 (Volume 48)
  - Pneumatic Fire Alarm Signals, 1904 (Volume 49)
  - Special Building Signals Class 3, Manhattan and Bronx, copy 1, undated (Volume 50)
  - Special Building Signals Class 3, Manhattan and Bronx, copy 2, undated (Volume 51)